Guide to the Women in the Urban Crisis Records, 1969-1984 AIS.1985.03
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Correspondence, 1969-1984; I.
  - Correspondenc U-V, 1969-1984; 8.
    - University of Pittsburgh, Center for Urban Research, 1975-1977 (Box 5, Folder 94)
    - University of Pittsburgh, Office of Urban and Community Services, 1972-1979 (Box 5, Folder 95)
    - University of Pittsburgh, Parliamentary Procedures, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 96)
    - University of Pittsburgh, School of Medicine, 1970-1981 (Box 5, Folder 97)
    - University of Pittsburgh, School of Social Work, 1971-1981 (Box 5, Folder 98)
    - University of Pittsburgh, Women's Center, 1972-1982 (Box 5, Folder 99)
    - University of Pittsburgh, Women's Study Program, 1972-1982 (Box 5, Folder 100)
    - University of Pittsburgh, Social Relations, undated (Box 5, Folder 101)
    - Upsher, Tony, undated (Box 5, Folder 102)
    - Urban Institute Survey, undated (Box 5, Folder 103)
    - Urban League of Pittsburgh, Inc., 1971-1976 (Box 5, Folder 104)
    - Urban Redevelopment Authority of Pittsburgh, 1970-1974 (Box 5, Folder 105)
    - Urban Task Force, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 106)
    - Urban Youth Action, Inc., 1969-1976 (Box 5, Folder 107)
    - V- Letters to Individuals, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 108)
    - Vectors/Pittsburgh (formerly Pgh. Jaycee's), 1970-1981 (Box 5, Folder 109)
    - Vesuvius Crucible Company, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 110)
    - Vibrations II-Committee for Penal Reform, 1971-1972 (Box 5, Folder 111)
    - Vintage Adult Day Care Center, 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 112)
    - Vista, undated (Box 5, Folder 113)
    - Vocational Rehabilitation Center, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 114)
    - Volunteer Action Center, 1973-1982 (Box 5, Folder 115)
    - Volunteer Viewpoints, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 116)
    - Volunteer in Progress, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 117)
    - Volunteer for Shirley Chisholm for President, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 118)
    - Volunteerism Conference, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 119)
    - Volunteerism, Department of, 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 120)
  - Correspondence W-Z, 1969-1984; 9.
    - W- Letters to Individuals, 1969-1984 (Box 5, Folder 121)
    - WAMO, 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 122)
    - Warren Village, Inc., 1984 (Box 5, Folder 123)
    - Warrendale Youth Development Center, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 124)
    - Washington Half-Way Home for Women, Inc., 1970 (Box 5, Folder 125)
    - Washington Intelligence Report, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 126)
    - WDVE Radio, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 127)
    - WEEP- Radio, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 128)
    - Welfare Rights Organization of Allegheny County, 1970-1981 (Box 5, Folder 129)
    - Western Pennsylvania Black Political Assembly, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 130)
    - Western Pennsylvania Coalition for Children's Survival, 1971-1972 (Box 5, Folder 131)
    - Western Pennsylvania Coalition for Human Needs and Rights, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 132)
    - Western Pennsylvania Fair Budget Coalition, 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 133)
    - Western Pennsylvania National Bank, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 134)
    - Western Pennsylvania Public Interest Research Group, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 135)
    - Western Pennsylvania Teen Challenge, 1971-1972 (Box 5, Folder 136)
    - Western Restoration Center, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 137)
    - Westinghouse Electric Corporation, 1970-1984 (Box 5, Folder 138)
    - Westmoreland County Clean Green Committee, 1971-1973 (Box 5, Folder 139)
    - White House Conference on Aging, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 140)
    - WIIC Television, 1971-1979 (Box 5, Folder 141)
    - Wildsisters, Inc., 1981 (Box 5, Folder 142)
    - Wilhelm Weinberg Seminar, Cornell University, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 143)
    - WJAS Radio, 1970-1972 (Box 5, Folder 144)
    - Wolff, Garwood R. Co., 1972 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Woman Kind, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Woman's Club of Forest Hills, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Womanspace- East, Inc., 1980 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Women Concerned for the Unborn Child, 1971-1972 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Women in Community Development, 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Women in Community Service, 1969-1981 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Women of Calvary Church, 1970-1978 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Women of St. Martin's, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Women Today, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Women USA, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Women's American Organization for Rehabilitation Through Training (ORT), Pittsburgh Region, 1970-1972 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Women's Association of the United Fund, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Women's Center-South, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Women's Center and Shelter of Greater Pittsburgh, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Women's Crusade Against Organized Crime, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Women's Development Corporation, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Women's Federation of the Third Presbyterian Church, 1970-1973 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Women's Group of the New American Movement, 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Women's Health Services, Inc., 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Women's Information Service and Exchange (WISE), 1974 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Women's Plea for Human Rights for Soviet Jewry, 1971-1981 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Women's Political Caucus, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Women's Society of Christian Service, Western Pennsylvania Conference, United Methodist Church, 1969-1971 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Woodville State Hospital, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - World Affairs Council of Pittsburgh, undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - World Peace Tax Fund, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - World's Greatest Fairshake Festival, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - WQED Public Broadcasting, 1969-1982 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - WTAE Radio and Television, 1971-1975 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - WWSW Radio, 1973-1980 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - WYEP Radio, 1974-1976 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Xerox Corporation, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Y-Letters to Individuals, 1969-1973 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Young Men and Women's Hebrew Association and Irene Kaufmann Centers (Y-IKC), 1973 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Young Women's Christian Association of Greater Pittsburgh (YWCA), 1969-1981 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Younger Center, Paul, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Youth City, 1971-1972 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Z-Letters to Individuals, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Zangrille Plumbing Company, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 40)
- Committees, II.
  This series is made up of the various ad hoc committees concerned with urban issues and committees related to the functioning of the organization itself that the Women in the Urban Crisis served on. Ad hoc committees were established for day care, education, employment, health, housing, and welfare. Committees pertaining to finance, fundraising, and nominating of officers were customary to meeting operational needs.
  - Ad Hoc Committee on School Board Selection, 1973-1976 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Committee for Open Media (COM), 1972 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Committee on Corporal Punishment, 1973-1975 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Committee, General, 1978-1982 (Box 6, Folder 44-47)
  - Day Care, Committee, 1970-1974, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 48-52)
  - Education, Committee, 1969-1982 (Box 6, Folder 53-65)
  - Education Publications Committee, 1969-1971 (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - Employment, Committee, 1969-1981 (Box 6, Folder 67-76)
  - Employment, Committee, 1969-1981 (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
  - Executive Committee, 1973-1974 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Finance Committee, 1970-1974 (Box 7, Folder 4-5)
  - Foundations, Committee, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Fundraising Committee, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Furniture Exchange Committee, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Health, Committee, 1970-1979 (Box 7, Folder 9-17)
  - Housing, Committee, 1969-1980 (Box 7, Folder 18-27)
  - Housing Directory Committee, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Nominating Committee, 1971-1984 (Box 7, Folder 29-37)
  - Personnel Committee, 1979-1982 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Volunteers Committee, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Welfare Committee, 1969-1976 (Box 7, Folder 40-46)
- Organizations and Subject Files, III.
  Brochures and information related to various local and national organizations and subjects are contained in this series. The items in this series served as resources for the organization on a wide array of social issues ranging from the criminal justice system to teenage pregnancy.
  - Affirmative Action, 1978-1982 (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Bail Reform, 1971-1982 (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - Brochure Requests, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - Bulletin Board, 1971-1972 (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - Cancer Calendar, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - Census, 1980-1981 (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - Child Care, 1983-1984 (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Children's Expo, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - Christmas Message, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Church Town, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - Citizen's Advisory Committee on Racial Equality to the Board of Education, Pittsburgh Public Schools, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - Citizens School Assembly, 1971-1972 (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - Coalition Against Cutbacks in Human Services, W. Moreland Co., 1981 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Coalition for Media Change, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Commission on Status of Women, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Committee for American-Iranian Crisis Resolution (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Common Cause, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Community Release Agency (RCA), 1971 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Consumer Information Service, 1980-1981 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Consumer Protection, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Criminal Justice System, 1971-1975 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Directors of Volunteers in Agencies (DOVIA), 1976 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Earth Day +1, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Education Statistics, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Energy, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Environment, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Equal Rights Amendment, 1970-1972 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Feminist Network, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Flea Market, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Florence Reizenstein Task Force, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Florence Reizenstein Human Relations Award, 1971-1973 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Food Labeling, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Foundation Information, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Garfield Area Outreach (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Gay and Lesbian Groups, 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - General, 1970-1973 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Governor's Annual Workforce Report, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Group Against Smog and Pollution (GASP), 1970-1971 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Hands Up, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Health Education, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Health and Welfare Funding Conference, 1976-1977 (Box 8, Folder 29-30)
  - Health Spirit, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Henry G. Frick Education Commission, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Heritage and Consumerism Project- Herron Hill Middle School, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Home for Crippled Children, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Home Rule Charter, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Hotlines for Help, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - PA Human Relations Commission, 1979-1980 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Hunger in America, 1968-1969 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Indian Rights, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - J. Shane Creamer (Attorney General), 1971 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Jaycees Christmas Shopping Project and Circus, 1969-1971 (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Juvenile Detention Home, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Kibbutz for street children, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - League of Women Voters (Pgh), 1971-1981 (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - Legal Reform, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - Legislation, 1971-1972 (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - Leisure-Learn, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - Meals on Wheels, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - Metropolitan Tenants' Organization, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - National Organization for Women (NOW), 1967-1970 (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - Negro Educational Emergency Drive Dinner and Reizenstein Award, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - Neighborhood Youth Corps, no date (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - New Professionals, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 53)
  - News Clippings, 1970-1984 (Box 8, Folder 54)
  - Parent Advisory Council Handbook, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 55)
  - Penal Reform, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 56)
  - Pennsylvania Program for Women and Girl Offenders, 1969-1971 (Box 8, Folder 57)
  - Pittsburgh Area Pre-School, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 58)
  - Pittsburgh School Board Selection, 1974-1975 (Box 8, Folder 59)
  - Rape Statutes, 1974-1975 (Box 8, Folder 60)
  - Resources, 1980-1985 (Box 8, Folder 61)
  - School Volunteer Association of Pittsburgh, no date (Box 8, Folder 62)
  - Special Projects, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 63)
  - St. Richard's School, no date (Box 8, Folder 64)
  - State Hearings, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 65)
  - Survival Manual, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 66)
  - Talent Referral Project, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 67)
  - Teenage Pregnancy, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 68)
  - United Nations Association of Pittsburgh, no date (Box 8, Folder 69)
  - United Way Pledge-A-Thon, 1975-1979 (Box 8, Folder 70)
  - Uptown Neighbors in Action, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 71)
  - Volunteer Handbook, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 72)
  - Volunteer Network, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 73)
- Organizational Files, IV.
  The organizational files are representative of the operation of WIUC. These files include information on the history of the organization and its various policies, the presidents' progress reports and records, and the treasurer's reports from 1972-1984. There are also files containing the minutes for the board of director's meetings from 1969-1984. Also of importance are the organizational monthly newsletters that range in date from 1974-1983, although records are intermittent for several months.
  - WIUC Organizational File, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - WIUC History and Funding, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - By-Laws, 1969-1970 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Parliamentary Pointers, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Policy, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Duties of Officers, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Priorities, no date (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - President's Progress Reports, 1971-1972 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Facilities, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Equipment, ca. 1970s (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Evaluation Day, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Evaluation Session, 1971-1974 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - MTE Poll, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Personnel Policy, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Volunteer Opportunities, 1970-1971 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Speaker's Bureau, 1972-1973 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - News Items, no date (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Public Relations, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Press Conferences, 1971-1972 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Press Releases, 1971-1972 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Newsletter Design, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Newsletter, 1974-1984 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Mailings, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Treasurer's Report, 1972-1983 (intermittent) (Box 9, Folder 24-33)
  - Delegate's Meetings, 1973-1984 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Executive Committee, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Board of Directors, 1973-1983 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Board Responsibility, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Notes to Board Members, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Agendas, 1969-1981 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1969-1984 (Box 9, Folder 40-55)
- Membership, V.
  This series contains a list of individual and constituent members. Constituent organizations range from groups representing local churches to local branches of national organizations. Members are accountable for paying yearly dues, where records can be found spanning the years 1970-1984.
  - Membership Lists, 1970-1974 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Membership Thank You Letters, no date (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Constituent Organizations, 1970-1984 (Box 10, Folder 3-4)
  - Constituent Relations, 1971-1972 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Dues and Membership Materials, 1970-1984 (Box 10, Folder 6-18)
- Annual Conferences, VI.
  Following the 1969 conference at Chatham College, WIUC held annual meetings through 1984. These meetings gathered together individual members and members from the constituent organizations to discuss the happenings of the year and where the organization was headed. Keynote speakers included Lt. Governor Ernest Kline in 1977 and Helen Payson Seager, the Director of the Pennsylvania Commission for Women in 1983.
  - WIUC Conference, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Annual Conference, 1970-1976 (Box 10, Folder 20-28)
  - Annual Conference, 1977-1984 (Box 11, Folder 1-9)
- Programs and Proposals, VII.
  This series provides records to the programs and proposals developed by the organization. The Hot Breakfast Program established at several area elementary schools from 1972-1981 was the first program of its kind in Pittsburgh. Another program that generated a large amount of records are the WPXI and WIIC Action Lines where members of WIUC would take phone calls and help resolve community issues by giving referrals to the individuals during 1982 and 1983. The 1972 WIUC Day Care Training Project offered training for family day care mothers in Allegheny County to further their knowledge of child care/development and provide an opportunity for participants to learn from each other based on their experiences. Another notable project was the Florence Reizenstein Task Force whose purpose was to alleviate racial tensions in area schools.
  - Guidelines for Proposals, 1972-1983 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Proposals- Special Projects, 1969-1972 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Proposals, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Community Action Pittsburgh Proposal, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - CETA Proposal, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Comprehensive Employment and Training Act Proposal, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Homework Hotline Proposal, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Neighborhood Assistance Act Proposal, 1973-1977 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Teen Mother Project Proposal, 1972-1978 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Voter's Registration Project and Proposal, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Call for Action, 1969-1976 (Box 11, Folder 20-25)
  - Camperships, 1971-1980 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Children's Corner, 1971-1974 (Box 11, Folder 27-28)
  - Conference on Families, 1979-1980 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Florence Reizenstein Task Force, 1970-1974 (Box 11, Folder 30-32)
  - Helpmobile- WJAS, 1970-1972 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Teen Pregnancy Conference, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 2-3)
  - School Lunch Coordinating Committee, 1969-1971 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Breakfast Program, 1970-1981 (intermittent) (Box 12, Folder 5-14)
  - Summer Breakfast Program, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Homewood Lunch Program, 1970-1972 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Larimer Lunch Program, 1970-1971 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Miller School Lunch Program, 1970-1981 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - St. Agnes Breakfast Program, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Breakfast Program Evaluation, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Northview Heights Breakfast Program, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - WPXI- Action Line, 1983-1984 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - General, 1980-1983 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Contact Notebook, undated (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Contact Note Cards, c. 1980 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Resources, c. 1976-1981 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Information, c. 1976-1983 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Resolved Action Line, 1981-1983 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Incomplete, 1978-1983 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Animals, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Automobile, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Consumers, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Credit, 1982-1983 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Education, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Employment, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Environmental Health, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Health, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Home Repairs, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Housing, 1981-1982 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Human Relations, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Information, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Insurance, 1982-1983 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Landlord and Neighbor, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Legal, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Parking, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Port Authority Transit (PAT), 1982 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Public Works, 1982-1983 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Social Security, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Taxes, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Television, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Traffic Police, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Utilities, c. 1982-1984 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Vacant Building, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Veterans Administration, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - Water- Flooding Sewage, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - Action Line Volunteers, c. 1982-1983 (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - Action Line Phone Log, 1982-1983 (Box 13, Folder 36-55)
  - Report on WIUC Family Day Care Mother Training Project, 1969-1972 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - General, 1970-1972 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Fact Sheet, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Family Day Care Mother Training Project, 1971-1973 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - WIUC Training Program, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Finances, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Licensing Regulations and Forms (State of Pennsylvania), 1969 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Legal, 1972-1973 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Letters From Natural Parents, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - List of Family Day Care Mothers- Licensed in Allegheny County, 1971-1972 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Day Care in Allegheny County, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Louise Child Care, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Publicity, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Sites, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Workshop Applications, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Applications for Non-Participants, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Program Participant List, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Workshop Attendance, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Vitae of Program Trainers, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Workshop Information, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Agendas, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Contract with McKeesport Area School, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Contracts with Trainers and Co-Trainers, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence with Consultants, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence with Day Care Mothers, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence with Louise Jackson, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence with Miscellaneous, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence with Trainers, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence with Co-Trainers, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Elected Members of Groups, undated (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - Executive Committee, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - List of films and slides related to child care/development, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - Pamphlets and Other Printed Materials, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - Backup Resources, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 35)
  - Sample Packet, 1969-1972 (Box 14, Folder 36)
  - Summary and Evaluation, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 37)
  - Post-Training Observation, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 38)
- Scrapbook, Photographs, and Slides, VIII.
  This series contains photographs and slides that illustrate the various programs, projects, and meetings. In addition, newspaper clippings are contained in a scrapbook.
  - Action Line Photos (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Breakfast Program Photos (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Health Spirit Photos, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Photos (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Scrapbook (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Award (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Award in Frame (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Slides (Box 15, Folder 8)
- Library Materials, 1896-1981; 1960-1981; IX.
  This series contains materials that came from Women in the Urban Crisis, via the University of Pittsburgh's Women's Studies department. They are resources that address many topics important to women's lives and the feminist movement in the 1960s-1980s. Government reports discuss major trends affecting women, especially labor statistics. Pamphlets, some produced by the federal or state government, some by independent organizations provide information regarding several topics of feminist concern including women's rights, financial proficiency, and child care. Newsletters and magazines also address these topics and offer examples of women's thoughts about and responses to them, featured in the articles, stories, and art they produced regarding these issues.